<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
	<p>
    This publication contains information to support implementers working across multiple versions
    of FHIR. Specifically, this publication contains the following information: 
  </p>
  <ul>
   <li>Maps: a series of <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}conceptmap.html">ConceptMap</a> resources that describe how resources, elements, codes, and search parameters relate to each other across versions</li>
   <li>Transforms: a series of <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}structuremap.html">StructureMap</a> resources that define executable transforms between the different versions</li>
   <li>Extensions: a series of <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}structuredefinition.html">StructureDefinition</a> resources that define the actual cross version extensions as described in the <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}versions.html#extensions">FHIR Specification</a></li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    This publication only contains derivative content based on the FHIR core specification publications, the FHIR Extension Pack, and <a href="http://terminology.hl7.org">the HL7 terminology</a>.  
    As such, this publication is not subject to ballot; it is released when signficant issues are found and fixed. Change requests or issues against this publication should be made against 
    the <a href="https://github.com/HL7/fhir-cross-version">GitHub repository</a>. Issues with this content can be discussed <a href="https://chat.fhir.org/#narrow/stream/426854-FHIR-cross-version-issues">here</a>.
  </p>
	<a name="finding"> </a>
  <h3>Finding Content</h3>
  <p>
  This publication has a lot of content in it. The quickest way to find anything is to 
  start at the cross-version resource table:
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="cross-version-summary.html">Cross-Version Resource Table</a></li>
  </ul>

  <h3>About the content</h3>
	<a name="mappings"> </a>
	<h4>Mappings</h4>
  <p>
   Notes about the Concept Maps:
  </p>
  <table class="grid">
   <tr>
    <td>Resources</td>
    <td>These map between the resources across FHIR versions. Content is added, deleted or moved, and the scope and intent of ther resources 
    changes subtly or significantly. Where the strength of the relationship is 'equivalent' (<code>=</code>), then the resource has 
    been renamed, but where the strength is 'source-is-broader-than-target' (<code>&gt;</code>) or 'source-is-narrower-than-target' (<code>&lt;</code>),
    that means that the scope of the resource has been changed, and data moved between them, or re-organized. The changes may be quite 
    significant in those cases. These relationships cannot be used as input to automated conversion engines.</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td>Elements</td>
    <td>These map between elements across FHIR versions. These relationships are based on the <i>definition</i> of the element. 
    Note that elements may be renamed, redefined, added, deleted or moved between versions, or the value domain (the set of valid values allowed in the element) may change
    between versions. Where the strength of the relationship is 'equivalent' (<code>=</code>), then the resource has 
    been renamed, but where the strength is 'source-is-broader-than-target' (<code>&gt;</code>) or 'source-is-narrower-than-target' (<code>&lt;</code>),
    that means that the definition of the element has been changed. The changes may be quite 
    significant in those cases. These relationships cannot be used as input to automated conversion engines even when the relationship is '=' because 
    these relationships do not account for the value domains of the elements.</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td>Codes</td>
    <td>These relationships are between the allowed codes for equivalent coded elements across FHIR versions, where the coding strength is 'required' or 'extensible'.
     Since these mappings are between 'concepts', the conceptual mappings are generally suitable for use by automated engines, and these mappings are used by the transforms.
     Note that even for these maps, manual review will always be needed when the relationship is not 'equivalent'</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td>Search Parameters</td>
    <td>These map between search parameters across versions. Search Parameters are generally more stable than the rest of the FHIR, but even 
    so, they may be renamed, redefined, or have a different type. The relationships defined in these mappings do not account for changes in the 
    value domains or functionality of the search parameters, only their conceptual definition.</td>
   </tr>
  </table>

	<a name="transforms"> </a>
	<h4>Transforms</h4>
  <p>
    The implementation scope of the conversion maps is fixed: implementing a proper transform from version to version.
  </p>
  <p>
    A known limitation of the transforms is that they do not produce or consume cross-version extensions, due to the 
    fact that they were written before the rest of the content in this IG was produced. Contributions in this regard 
    will be welcome.
  </p>

	<a name="extensions"> </a>
	<h4>Extensions</h4>
  <p>
  Cross version extensions. The extensions are derived from the definitions above. 
  Only valid extensions are defined - those that contain content not valid in other versions. 
  See [x] for the logic pertaining to which FHIR elements across the versions are considered 
  to be valid cross-version extensions. 
  </p>
  <p>
  The cross version extensions are defined in this single publication that contains all of them,
  which version they are valid for; these definitions are found in the package <code>hl7.fhir.uv.xver</code>.
  In addition, this publication also produces the following additional packages:
  </p>
  <ul>
   <li><code>hl7.fhir.uv.xver.r2</code>: All the extensions valid to use against R2, in R2 format</li>
   <li><code>hl7.fhir.uv.xver.r3</code>: All the extensions valid to use against R3, in R3 format</li>
   <li><code>hl7.fhir.uv.xver.r4</code> All the extensions valid to use against R4, in R4 format</li>
   <li><code>hl7.fhir.uv.xver.r4b</code> All the extensions valid to use against R4B, in R4B format</li>
   <li><code>hl7.fhir.uv.xver.r5</code> All the extensions valid to use against R5, in R5 format</li>
  </ul>
  <p>
  </p>

	<a name="ip"> </a>
	<h3>Intellectual Property Considerations</h3>
	<p>
    This implementation guide and the underlying FHIR specification are licensed as public domain under the <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}license.html#license">FHIR license</a>.  The
    license page also describes rules for the use of the FHIR name and logo.
  </p>
  <p>    
    This guide includes content that references external IP such as from LOINC and SNOMED CT that have more restrictive licensing requirements.  
    Implementers should make themselves familiar with licensing and any other constraints of terminologies used as part of their implementation process.  
    In some cases, licensing requirements may limit the systems that data captured using certain codes may be shared with.
  </p>
  {% include ip-statements.xhtml %}
  
<div style="display: none">
  <a name="igs"> </a>
  <h3>Dependencies</h3>
  <p>
    This IG depends on the following additional IGs:
  </p>
  
  {%include dependency-table-short.xhtml %}


  {%include globals-table.xhtml %}
</div>

</div>